<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Broadcasting Software on</title><link>/docs/broadcasting/</link><description>Recent content in Broadcasting Software on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><atom:link href="/docs/broadcasting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>OBS/Streamlabs OBS</title><link>/docs/broadcasting/obs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/broadcasting/obs/</guid><description>OBS is a popular piece of free software that will get you streaming from your own computer right away.
Install OBS or Streamlabs OBS and get it working with your local setup. Open OBS Settings and go to &amp;ldquo;Stream&amp;rdquo;. Select &amp;ldquo;Custom&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; as the service. Enter the URL of the server running your streaming service in the format of rtmp://myserver.net/live. Enter your &amp;ldquo;Stream Key&amp;rdquo; that matches a stream key defined in the Owncast admin.</description></item><item><title>Restream.io</title><link>/docs/broadcasting/restream/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/broadcasting/restream/</guid><description>You must be a paid user of Restream to point to your Owncast instance as a destination &amp;ldquo;channel&amp;rdquo;.
Login and go to the &amp;ldquo;Add Channel&amp;rdquo; screen. Select &amp;ldquo;Custom RTMP&amp;rdquo; Add your server information in the format of rtmp://myserver/live for the RTMP URL and your Stream Key.</description></item><item><title>Zoom</title><link>/docs/broadcasting/zoom/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/broadcasting/zoom/</guid><description>Zoom offers to stream your meeting to a livestreaming service like Owncast. Please mind that some changes might need to be done by your Zoom administrator.
Set up Owncast and configure it by your choosing. Since the RMTP stream comes directly from the Zoom servers, at least the RMTP port should be available from the internet. Allow live streaming for the user account. In zoom.us/profile/setting, scroll down to &amp;ldquo;Allow live streaming meetings&amp;rdquo; and activate Custom Live Streaming Service: Schedule a meeting using the website and save it.</description></item><item><title>ffmpeg</title><link>/docs/broadcasting/ffmpeg/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/broadcasting/ffmpeg/</guid><description>Streaming with ffmpeg is quite easy. You can stream any connected webcam or HDMI grabber that appears in /dev/video* and incoming alsa audio devices. In this example, the /dev/video2 video device and the hw:1,0 alsa audio device are used:
ffmpeg -f alsa -ac 2 -i hw:1,0 -thread_queue_size 64 \ -f v4l2 -framerate 60 -video_size 1280x720 -input_format yuyv422 -i /dev/video2 \ -c:v libx264 -preset veryfast -b:v 1984k -maxrate 1984k -bufsize 3968k \ -vf &amp;#34;format=yuv420p&amp;#34; -g 60 -c:a aac -b:a 128k -ar 44100 \ -f flv rtmp://&amp;lt;ip-of-your-server&amp;gt;/live/&amp;lt;your-streaming-key&amp;gt;</description></item><item><title>Compatible hardware</title><link>/docs/broadcasting/hardware/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/broadcasting/hardware/</guid><description>The following hardware with native live streaming have been tested and work.
GoPro Hero 8 Mevo ATEM Mini Pro TriCaster Mini *you have to send the Stream Key as an unencrypted parameter called &amp;ldquo;Stream ID&amp;rdquo; Kiloview E1 Blackmagic Web Presenter HD If you have tested other hardware with Owncast we&amp;rsquo;d love to hear about it!</description></item><item><title>Jitsi</title><link>/docs/broadcasting/jitsi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/broadcasting/jitsi/</guid><description>Jitsi is both a video conferencing provider and a software suite. It is open source and can be self-hosted. It is also available as a service at meet.jit.si.
Visit your Jitsi meeting page. Click on the three dots in the lower right. Select &amp;ldquo;Start live stream&amp;rdquo; In the &amp;ldquo;Start a live screen&amp;rdquo; modal put your full Owncast RTMP in the &amp;ldquo;Live stream key&amp;rdquo; field. This would be in the format of rtmp://your-owncast-server/live/yourkey.</description></item></channel></rss>