<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Owncast on</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content in Owncast on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Build on top of Owncast</title><link>/thirdparty/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/thirdparty/</guid><description>💡 Note: while we will strive to keep these APIs as stable as possible, it's still early days with our integration hooks. As we learn more and continue to make things that are useful to other developers we may need to make changes or break functionality. It's recommended if you're building on top of Owncast to stay current with the discussions and updates around the project and let us know how things are going.</description></item><item><title>News</title><link>/news/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 12:36:22 -0800</pubDate><guid>/news/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Quickstart_olds</title><link>/quickstart_old/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 20:11:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>/quickstart_old/</guid><description/></item><item><title>About the Owncast Project</title><link>/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/about/</guid><description>In 2020 the world changed when everyone become stuck in their homes, looking for creative outlets to share their art, skills and themselves from inside their bedroom.
This created an explosion of live streaming on Facebook Live, YouTube Live, Instagram, and Twitch. These services provided everything they needed, an easy way to live stream to the world, and a chat for users to be a part of their community.
There deserves to be a better option for people.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/contact/</guid><description>Fediverse: @owncast@fosstodon.org
Use any of the below options to get in touch with the Owncast team. If you&amp;rsquo;re experiencing issues please open an issue. Drop by our chat if you&amp;rsquo;d like to talk with Owncast community members or want to talk through something in real time with those who may be able to help.
Bug Tracker For any bugs or issues you&amp;rsquo;d like to file with the project.
Community Chat If you have any general usage or support questions, you&amp;rsquo;ll find responses in our chat, where other users and developers hang out.</description></item><item><title>Contribute</title><link>/contribute/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/contribute/</guid><description>We are open for new contributors to this project. If you have found issues or bugs, or would like to improve Owncast by sending your code, please visit our GitHub page:
GitHub Repository The team also gets on Jitsi regularily, so if you want to attend of those meetings, check out issue #167 where we coordinate meeting times.
Contributor Covenant Code of Conduct Our Pledge In the interest of fostering an open and welcoming environment, we as contributors and maintainers pledge to making participation in our project and our community a harassment-free experience for everyone, regardless of age, body size, disability, ethnicity, sex characteristics, gender identity and expression, level of experience, education, socio-economic status, nationality, personal appearance, race, religion, or sexual identity and orientation.</description></item><item><title>Documentation</title><link>/docs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/</guid><description>For most people Owncast will be completely usable out of the box without additional configuration. Simply following the Quickstart will have you streaming in minutes.
There are, however, handfuls of items you can configure to tweak the content of your page, the video quality, server performance and more.
You can also extend Owncast&amp;rsquo;s functionality by building your own bots, overlays, tools and integrations by taking advantage of the third party APIs.</description></item><item><title>Donated Owncast servers</title><link>/donated/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/donated/</guid><description>If you or your organization has content to share with the world, but doesn&amp;rsquo;t have the experience or resources required to run an Owncast server, we may be able to offer one, free of charge.
Our Goal Aligning with our mission to create a streaming option that lives outside the large corporate services, we would like to offer a small number of free, hosted instances to streamers.
Our resources are limited, and we&amp;rsquo;ll be picky and start small.</description></item><item><title>Examples</title><link>/examples/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/examples/</guid><description/></item><item><title>FAQ</title><link>/faq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/faq/</guid><description>1. Who is this for? Owncast is for people who are live streamers, or who wants to host live streams for others. It&amp;rsquo;s a &amp;ldquo;one to many&amp;rdquo; broadcast much like Twitch, Facebook Live, YouTube Live, etc.
2. Who or what is this not for? Owncast is not for video conferencing or any use case where multiple people are wanting to see video of each other. It&amp;rsquo;s also not a good choice if you have tight real-time requirements as HLS video has inherent delays.</description></item><item><title>Help contribute to Owncast!</title><link>/help/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/help/</guid><description>Owncast is a growing open source project that is giving freedom, flexibility and fun to live streamers. And while we have a small team of kind, talented and thoughtful volunteers, we have gaps in our skillset that we&amp;rsquo;d love to fill so we can get even better at building tools that make a difference for people.
We abide by our Code of Conduct and feel strongly about open, appreciative, and empathetic people joining us.</description></item><item><title>Owncast Demo Servers</title><link>/demo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/demo/</guid><description>We provide two public Owncast servers for you to see how it works. One for streaming to and one for just watching.
Stream your content to broadcast.owncast.online You can point your own software and content at broadcast.owncast.online to test live streaming with Owncast. Go there and find the current key in the description and chat messages.
Read more about how to configure your software by reading the broadcasting software documentation.</description></item><item><title>Owncast Quickstart</title><link>/quickstart/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/quickstart/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Owncast Releases</title><link>/releases/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/releases/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>