<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Owncast on</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content in Owncast on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Build on top of Owncast</title><link>/thirdparty/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/thirdparty/</guid><description>💡 Note: while we will strive to keep these APIs as stable as possible, it's still early days with our integration hooks. As we learn more and continue to make things that are useful to other developers we may need to make changes or break functionality. It's recommended if you're building on top of Owncast to stay current with the discussions and updates around the project and let us know how things are going.</description></item><item><title>Quickstart_olds</title><link>/quickstart_old/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 20:11:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>/quickstart_old/</guid><description/></item><item><title>About the Owncast Project</title><link>/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/about/</guid><description>In 2020 the world changed when everyone become stuck in their homes, looking for creative outlets to share their art, skills and themselves from inside their bedroom.
This created an explosion of live streaming on Facebook Live, YouTube Live, Instagram, and Twitch. These services provided everything they needed, an easy way to live stream to the world, and a chat for users to be a part of their community.
There deserves to be a better option for people.</description></item><item><title>Chat one-on-one about Owncast</title><link>/1-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/1-1/</guid><description>The best way for Owncast to be something that&amp;rsquo;s useful to the most people is to hear what people have to say.
We have periodic group calls and events, but it&amp;rsquo;s not always the easiest way to get your personal story, idea, or question heard so here is an opportunity to chat about Owncast on a personal video call.
If you are a current or prospective Owncast streamer who is interested in providing thoughts, feedback, or have questions to ask one-on-one we want to know what you have to say.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/contact/</guid><description>Fediverse: @owncast@fosstodon.org
Use any of the below options to get in touch with the Owncast team. If you&amp;rsquo;re experiencing issues please open an issue. Drop by our chat if you&amp;rsquo;d like to talk with Owncast community members or want to talk through something in real time with those who may be able to help.
Bug Tracker For any bugs or issues you&amp;rsquo;d like to file with the project.
Community Chat If you have any general usage or support questions, you&amp;rsquo;ll find responses in our chat, where other users and developers hang out.</description></item><item><title>Contribute</title><link>/contribute/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/contribute/</guid><description>Click here if you are not redirected.</description></item><item><title>Documentation</title><link>/docs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/</guid><description>For most people Owncast will be completely usable out of the box without additional configuration. Simply following the Quickstart will have you streaming in minutes.
There are, however, handfuls of items you can configure to tweak the content of your page, the video quality, server performance and more.
You can also extend Owncast&amp;rsquo;s functionality by building your own bots, overlays, tools and integrations by taking advantage of the third party APIs.</description></item><item><title>Donated Owncast servers</title><link>/donated/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/donated/</guid><description>If you or your organization has content to share with the world, but doesn&amp;rsquo;t have the experience or resources required to run an Owncast server, we may be able to offer one, free of charge.
Our Goal Aligning with our mission to create a streaming option that lives outside the large corporate services, we would like to offer a small number of free, hosted instances to streamers.
Our resources are limited, and we&amp;rsquo;ll be picky and start small.</description></item><item><title>Examples</title><link>/examples/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/examples/</guid><description/></item><item><title>FAQ</title><link>/faq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/faq/</guid><description>1. Who is this for? Owncast is for people who are live streamers, or who wants to host live streams for others. It&amp;rsquo;s a &amp;ldquo;one to many&amp;rdquo; broadcast much like Twitch, Facebook Live, YouTube Live, etc.
2. Who or what is this not for? Owncast is not for video conferencing or any use case where multiple people are wanting to see video of each other. It&amp;rsquo;s also not a good choice if you have tight real-time requirements as HLS video has inherent delays.</description></item><item><title>Help contribute to Owncast!</title><link>/help/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/help/</guid><description>Owncast is a growing open source project that is giving freedom, flexibility and fun to live streamers.
Unfortunately the project is lacking in contributors and there&amp;rsquo;s gaps in skillsets that we&amp;rsquo;d love to fill so we can get even better at building tools that make a difference for people.
Current needs Web frontend development. UI Accessibility knowledge. Web UI/UX and layout. Experienced Go developer to help level-up the backend. If you want to be a part of a project that a lot of people think is pretty cool, please reach out.</description></item><item><title>How to work on Owncast</title><link>/development/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/development/</guid><description>Click here if you are not redirected.</description></item><item><title>Owncast and your privacy</title><link>/privacy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/privacy/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s make this simple.
If you run an Owncast server, you run your own software, therefore we don&amp;rsquo;t know who you are or what you&amp;rsquo;re doing. If you opt to be listed in the Owncast directory, everything we know about you is what is listed publicly. When you access our web servers, such as reading documentation or visiting the Owncast directory, we count the number of views. You can see everything we see by visiting our web analytics page.</description></item><item><title>Owncast APIs</title><link>/api/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/api/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Owncast Contributor T-Shirt</title><link>/tshirt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/tshirt/</guid><description>Thank you! Thank you for contributing to, supporting, using, and being a part of the Owncast community. As a small token the project would like to offer you a free Owncast t-shirt.
There are two different styles to select from. Please let Gabe know if you have any questions. While he knows nothing about t-shirts he will do his best to help.
Click the direct link if you&amp;rsquo;d prefer not to use the tiny iframe embed of the shirt design.</description></item><item><title>Owncast Newsletter</title><link>/newsletter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/newsletter/</guid><description>Keep updated with the Owncast community With the Owncast community growing it can be difficult to keep track of all the different streamers, special events, tools, and new initiatives around all things Owncast. We plan to send out a newsletter periodically with project updates and featured community content. We'll never spam you or sell your email address. You can unsubscribe at any time. If you'd like to be involved in the creation of this newsletter, and submit ideas for the next issue, drop by the Owncast community chat and join the conversation!</description></item><item><title>Owncast public roadmap</title><link>/roadmap/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/roadmap/</guid><description>While nothing is set in stone, Owncast tries to set a relatively clear roadmap for future work and features. This enables the project to discuss things far in advance to make the best possible decisions as well as allowing Owncast users to know what types of updates they can expect. As time goes on planning for specific releases get more detailed, and it's very common for additional, smaller, releases to get slipped in between larger features to fix bugs and address feedback.</description></item><item><title>Owncast Quickstart</title><link>/quickstart/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/quickstart/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Owncast Releases</title><link>/releases/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/releases/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Participate in Hacktoberfest with Owncast</title><link>/hacktoberfest/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/hacktoberfest/</guid><description>Some of the information about Hacktoberfest was copied here from the official Hacktoberfest website and should be referenced for more information.
What is Hacktoberfest? Hacktoberfest is the annual event that encourages people to contribute to Open Source throughout October. Much of modern tech relies on open-source projects built and maintained by passionate people who often don’t have the staff or budgets to do much more than keep the project alive.</description></item><item><title>Trademark Policy</title><link>/trademark/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/trademark/</guid><description>This document outlines the rules for using Owncast&amp;rsquo;s trademarks. While our software is distributed under a free and open-source license, this does not give an automatic right to use our trademarks in all cases. Trademarks serve to identify the origin of products and services, so it’s important they are used correctly.
You may use our trademarks under certain conditions outlined here. If your use is not described in this document, it is either not allowed, or you will need to seek permission.</description></item><item><title>Troubleshoot Common Problems</title><link>/troubleshoot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/troubleshoot/</guid><description/></item><item><title>User Experience Designer wanted!</title><link>/designer-wanted/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/designer-wanted/</guid><description>Owncast is a growing free and open source live video streaming and chat project available for those who have live streaming needs. This includes anything from corporate events, game streams, school events, musicians, wedding venues, churches, TV stations, and more.
With the number of streamers and viewers growing, and new features on the horizon, the project is looking to add a dedicated user experience designer to help us focus on the experience of streamers and viewers alike.</description></item></channel></rss>