<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Owncast</title><link>http://owncast.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Owncast</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://owncast.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Owncast v0.0.1</title><link>http://owncast.github.io/posts/owncast-0.1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://owncast.github.io/posts/owncast-0.1/</guid><description>In honor of &lt;a href="https://github.com/mattdsteele">@mattdsteele&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://github.com/mattdsteele">@JCake&lt;/a> live streaming their wedding using Owncast tomorrow, here&amp;rsquo;s the first release version.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://owncast.github.io/docs/configuration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://owncast.github.io/docs/configuration/</guid><description>Configuration # The default config.yaml has a handful of values you can change. However, more can be customized if you need them to be. Some common changes to the config are:
Your site name, logo, description and external links. The stream key to gain access to broadcasting to your stream. The path to your specific ffmpeg executable. Video quality settings. S3 file storage. An example config file with additional features can be viewed below.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://owncast.github.io/docs/encoding/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://owncast.github.io/docs/encoding/</guid><description>Encoding with Owncast # It&amp;rsquo;s hard to give specific settings that will give you the best quality and performance with Owncast because people have different servers and requirements. However, this document aims to outline what is being done to your content and the different knobs you can tweak to get the best output for your instance..
But first the basics.
What is an Owncast powered live stream? # Owncast takes your source stream and converts it to short, individual video segments.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://owncast.github.io/docs/faq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://owncast.github.io/docs/faq/</guid><description>Frequently Asked Questions # 1. Who is this for? # Owncast is for people who are live streamers, or who wants to host live streams for others. It&amp;rsquo;s a &amp;ldquo;one to many&amp;rdquo; broadcast much like Twitch, Facebook Live, YouTube Live, etc.
2. Who or what is this not for? # Owncast is not for video conferencing or any use case where multiple people are wanting to see video of each other.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://owncast.github.io/docs/quickstart/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://owncast.github.io/docs/quickstart/</guid><description>Quickstart # There are two quick ways to get up and running, depending on your preference. One is to simply download the service and run it, and the other is through Docker, if Docker is your thing.
Download and run a release # Install ffmpeg if you haven&amp;rsquo;t. Make a directory to run the service from, and download a release from https://github.com/gabek/owncast/releases into that directory. Unzip the release&amp;rsquo;s archive for linux or macOS: unzip owncast-linux-x.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://owncast.github.io/docs/restream/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://owncast.github.io/docs/restream/</guid><description>Restream.io # If you&amp;rsquo;re a paid user of Restream you can point it at your Ownstream instance as another place to braodcast to.
Login and go to the &amp;ldquo;Add Channel&amp;rdquo; screen. Select &amp;ldquo;Custom RTMP&amp;rdquo; Add your server information in the format of rtmp://myserver/live for the RTMP URL and the Stream Key that matches what is in your config.yaml file.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://owncast.github.io/docs/s3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://owncast.github.io/docs/s3/</guid><description>Owncast with S3 # Here are some setup details, general information and tips specific to using external storage.
Choose your storage provider of choice. Yours not listed? File an issue and we&amp;rsquo;ll test and write up some documentation for it.
Linode Object Storage AWS S3 Wasabi Linode Object Storage # 250 GB storage + 1 TB Outbound Transfer for $5/mo.
Linode Object Storage is a good choice if you&amp;rsquo;re already using Linode to host your server.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>http://owncast.github.io/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://owncast.github.io/contact/</guid><description>Contact # Gabe Kangas
Mastodon: @gabek@mastodon.socialEmail: gabek@real-ity.com
Questions or bug reports # We have a open discussion board for questions, bugs and feature requests. Just open an issue :)
Issues on GitHub For security incidents, please send an email to Gabe (see above).</description></item><item><title>Contribute</title><link>http://owncast.github.io/contribute/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://owncast.github.io/contribute/</guid><description>Contribute to Owncast # We are open for new contributors to this project. If you have found issues or bugs, or would like to improve Owncast by sending your code, please visit our GitHub page:
GitHub Repository Contributor Covenant Code of Conduct # Our Pledge # In the interest of fostering an open and welcoming environment, we as contributors and maintainers pledge to making participation in our project and our community a harassment-free experience for everyone, regardless of age, body size, disability, ethnicity, sex characteristics, gender identity and expression, level of experience, education, socio-economic status, nationality, personal appearance, race, religion, or sexual identity and orientation.</description></item></channel></rss>