<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>News on</title><link>/news/</link><description>Recent content in News on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 12:36:22 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>v0.0.11 adds chat moderators.</title><link>/news/20220311-chat-moderators/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 12:36:22 -0800</pubDate><guid>/news/20220311-chat-moderators/</guid><description>You can now add moderators without granting access to your Owncast admin.
In your admin Visit Chat &amp;amp; Users &amp;gt; Users to find the user you want to grant Moderator privileges. Bring up their details and you can add them as a moderator.
By default there are no moderators, so at the very least you might want to make yourself one. However, you can always continue to moderate your chat via the admin, if you&amp;rsquo;d prefer.</description></item><item><title>Welcome to the Fediverse, Owncast streamers!</title><link>/news/20220305-welcome-to-the-fediverse/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/news/20220305-welcome-to-the-fediverse/</guid><description>Owncast v0.0.11 is now available, and with it brings Owncast to the Fediverse.
With these features people can follow your server and get alerted to when you go live. Additionally, as people engage with your live notifications outside of your server it will show up in your chat. This encourages people to share your stream and get a bit of recognition for doing so.
You can also compose posts within the Owncast admin to send to your followers, alerting people to your stream plans, or to remind followers that you&amp;rsquo;re still streaming and to come visit, for example.</description></item><item><title>How Do You Use Owncast?</title><link>/news/202217-how-do-you-use-owncast/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 17:19:16 -0800</pubDate><guid>/news/202217-how-do-you-use-owncast/</guid><description>Could you take a second and answer two very short questions to help influence the future of Owncast?
We want to build things that are most useful to you, but to do that we&amp;rsquo;d like to hear, generally, what category of streaming you&amp;rsquo;ve been using Owncast for.
Answer here. Your time and feedback is much appreciated!</description></item></channel></rss>