<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>S3 Storage on</title><link>/docs/storage/</link><description>Recent content in S3 Storage on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><atom:link href="/docs/storage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>AWS S3</title><link>/docs/storage/aws/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/storage/aws/</guid><description>AWS S3 is a good choice if you&amp;rsquo;re already using AWS for your server or are comfortable using AWS for other things. If you&amp;rsquo;re brand new to object storage and not using AWS already I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I&amp;rsquo;d recommend jumping into it just for Owncast. There are other options.
Here&amp;rsquo;s some example usage and pricing for AWS S3:
Create an S3 Bucket https://s3.console.aws.amazon.com/s3
Uncheck &amp;ldquo;Block all public access&amp;rdquo; since you want all files to be readable.</description></item><item><title>Backblaze B2</title><link>/docs/storage/backblaze/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 20:11:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>/docs/storage/backblaze/</guid><description>As of November 2020 Backblaze&amp;rsquo;s B2 is fully S3 compatible.
B2&amp;rsquo;s first 10G of storage is free, and the first 1G of download per day is free after that. Afterwards they charge $0.01/G.
Keys When creating your &amp;ldquo;Application Keys&amp;rdquo; keep in mind that the &amp;ldquo;Application Key ID&amp;rdquo; is the &amp;ldquo;Access Key&amp;rdquo; and the &amp;ldquo;Application Key&amp;rdquo; is the &amp;ldquo;Secret&amp;rdquo;.
It has been suggested that you make sure you set your key setting of &amp;ldquo;Allow access to Bucket&amp;rdquo; to All.</description></item><item><title>Digital Ocean Spaces</title><link>/docs/storage/digitalocean/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 20:11:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>/docs/storage/digitalocean/</guid><description>250 GB storage + 1 TB Outbound Transfer for $5/mo.
Digital Ocean Spaces is a good choice if you&amp;rsquo;re already using DigitalOcean to host your server. It should be fast to transfer your video from your server to their storage service, and their pricing will probably just be the flat $5/mo for you, so it&amp;rsquo;s easy to know what you&amp;rsquo;re paying.
Create a new bucket in the DigitalOcean console. Edit your storage config and change the S3 endpoint.</description></item><item><title>Wasabi</title><link>/docs/storage/wasabi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 20:11:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>/docs/storage/wasabi/</guid><description>Please read the following link before using.
&amp;ldquo;However, we do not recommend the playback of video directly from object storage (Wasabi or AWS S3) as the costs may be higher than expected and the delivery quality will be sub-optimal (as compared to solutions that pair object storage with a CDN and/or encoding/decoding functions).&amp;rdquo; -Wasabi Most people would end up paying $5.99/mo with Wasabi, and there&amp;rsquo;s no additional costs for the amount of people or amount of times people access your video.</description></item><item><title>Cloudfare R2</title><link>/docs/storage/cloudfare/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 18:20:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/storage/cloudfare/</guid><description>Cloudflare R2 Object Storage is S3-compatible
Cloudfare R2 gives you the freedom to create the multi-cloud architectures you desire with an S3-compatible global object storage.
**⚠️ This provider doesn&amp;rsquo;t currently support object lifecycles so if you don&amp;rsquo;t handle the deletion of unused objects yourself you&amp;rsquo;ll be paying for more storage than necessary.**
Pricing R2 provides zero-cost egress for stored objects — no matter your request rate
Here&amp;rsquo;s a snapshot of usage and pricing for Cloudflare R2:</description></item><item><title>Vultr Object Storage</title><link>/docs/storage/vultr/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 01:11:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>/docs/storage/vultr/</guid><description>If you require S3 object storage services and already use Vultr as your hosting provider it might make sense to use their object storage offering as well, since the connection between your Owncast server and your storage provider will be fast.
CORS You will need to follow Vultr&amp;rsquo;s instructions to enable CORS, so your Owncast player will have access to the video.
Setup s3cmd Follow Vultr&amp;rsquo;s documentation on setting up s3cmd so you can configure your object storage bucket.</description></item><item><title>Linode Object Storage</title><link>/docs/storage/linode/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 20:11:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>/docs/storage/linode/</guid><description>250 GB storage + 1 TB Outbound Transfer for $5/mo.
Linode Object Storage is a good choice if you&amp;rsquo;re already using Linode to host your server. It should be fast to transfer your video from your server to their storage service, and their pricing will probably just be the flat $5/mo for you, so it&amp;rsquo;s easy to know what you&amp;rsquo;re paying.
Create a new bucket at the Linode Object Storage admin page.</description></item><item><title>Minio</title><link>/docs/storage/minio/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 20:11:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>/docs/storage/minio/</guid><description>If you want to host the video segments on a self hosted S3 compatible MinIO server, you get even more control over your data.
Bucket Create a bucket, e.g. with the MinIO client by
get the two strings [YOUR-ACCESS-KEY] and [YOUR-SECRET-KEY] from your MinIO deployment. (Sometimes they are referred to as ROOT USER and KEY) add an alias mc alias set &amp;lt;ALIAS&amp;gt; &amp;lt;YOUR-S3-ENDPOINT&amp;gt; [YOUR-ACCESS-KEY] [YOUR-SECRET-KEY] create a new bucket mc mb &amp;lt;ALIAS&amp;gt;/stream allow downloading from bucket mc policy set download &amp;lt;ALIAS&amp;gt;/stream CORS Make sure to allow access to the buckets file from your owncast domain.</description></item><item><title>Oracle Cloud Object Storage</title><link>/docs/storage/oracle/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/storage/oracle/</guid><description>AWS S3 compatible Oracle Cloud Object Storage (https://www.oracle.com/cloud/storage/object-storage/) is a great choice when you don&amp;rsquo;t want to invest cash, because it contains 10GB of storage in Always Free Tier (https://www.oracle.com/cloud/free/#always-free).
Create a Bucket Go to https://cloud.oracle.com/object-storage/buckets Click &amp;ldquo;Create Bucket&amp;rdquo; Give name Leave the other options default After creating click on bucket name Click &amp;ldquo;Edit visibility&amp;rdquo; Choose &amp;ldquo;Public&amp;rdquo; Click &amp;ldquo;Save changes&amp;rdquo; Copy &amp;amp; save &amp;ldquo;Namespace&amp;rdquo; (see: picture below) Create an expiration policy You should expire old segments on your Bucket.</description></item><item><title>Contabo Object Storage</title><link>/docs/storage/contabo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/storage/contabo/</guid><description>Contabo Object Storage is S3 compatible and a good choice if you have a lot of viewers and a small budget, because there are no data transfer fees. You only have to pay for the storage capacity, starting at $2.49/month for 250 GB. Outbound traffic is routed through Cloudflare CDN. The data center is located in EU-Central. Other locations will be available soon.
Create a Bucket Go to Object Storage (Buckets) Click &amp;ldquo;Create Bucket&amp;rdquo; Enter a bucket name and confirm with &amp;ldquo;Create Bucket&amp;rdquo; On the &amp;ldquo;Quick Action&amp;rdquo; column click the share button and enable the &amp;ldquo;Make public&amp;rdquo; option After that it should look like this:</description></item></channel></rss>