<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Gabe Kangas on</title><link>/contributors/gabe-kangas/</link><description>Recent content in Gabe Kangas on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/contributors/gabe-kangas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Owncast v0.0.5</title><link>/releases/owncast-0.0.5/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/releases/owncast-0.0.5/</guid><description>Owncast v0.0.5 focuses primarily on some basic chat moderation, enabling the admin to remove chat messages
Upgrade instructions from 0.0.4 Stop the service from running. Backup your config.yaml and any other files you may have customized and want to save or refer to later. Move the zip file of 0.0.5 to your previous install location. Unzip the file, allowing it to overwrite old files. Restart the service. Changelog Owncast Core:</description></item><item><title>Owncast v0.0.4</title><link>/releases/owncast-0.0.4/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/releases/owncast-0.0.4/</guid><description>v0.0.4 includes several small updates and bug fixes. Also, you can now set a custom RTMP port and use our prepared builds for ARM computers like the Raspberry PI. With our notification feature, your visitors can see that a stream has started and that new chat messages were written while they were in other tabs.
Upgrade instructions from 0.0.3 Stop the service from running. Backup your config.yaml and any other files you may have customized and want to save or refer to later.</description></item><item><title>Owncast v0.0.3</title><link>/releases/owncast-0.0.3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/releases/owncast-0.0.3/</guid><description>v0.0.3 has a new admin dashboard to help get an overview of the configuration and performance of your Owncast server along with handfuls of additional updates.
Owncast Admin v0.0.3 introduces the web admin dashboard that you can use to get an overview of your owncast server.
Visit /admin and login with admin as the username and your stream key as the password.
We will continue to add functionality to this over time, so please let us know how it works for you and if you have any feedback.</description></item><item><title>Owncast v0.0.2</title><link>/releases/owncast-0.0.2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/releases/owncast-0.0.2/</guid><description>v0.0.2 has a bunch of updates, mostly focused on the web frontend.
Major changes Rewrite of the web interface with Preact, removing Vue. [#103] Add support for embedding chat externally. [#96] Add support for embedding the video player externally. [#110] Your username will get highlighted in chat when mentioned. [#100] Emoji picker w/ custom emoji support. [#86] Autocomplete usernames in composing chat messages by hitting tab. [#99] Improve support for autolinking, and embedding YouTube or Instagram links in chat.</description></item><item><title>Owncast v0.0.1</title><link>/releases/owncast-0.0.1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/releases/owncast-0.0.1/</guid><description>In honor of @mattdsteele and @JCake live streaming their wedding using Owncast tomorrow, here&amp;rsquo;s the first release version.
We&amp;rsquo;ve been testing, doing events and enjoying using Owncast, so I think it&amp;rsquo;s time to have a release version that others can start using as well.
Still lots of exciting updates going on, but here&amp;rsquo;s finally something that you can start using. Feel free to reach out and let us know what you&amp;rsquo;re using Owncast for, or if you have any questions.</description></item></channel></rss>