<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Owncast Quickstart on</title><link>/quickstart/</link><description>Recent content in Owncast Quickstart on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><atom:link href="/quickstart/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Manual Install</title><link>/quickstart/manual/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 20:11:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>/quickstart/manual/</guid><description> Make a directory to run the service from, and download a release from https://github.com/owncast/owncast/releases into that directory. Unzip the release. Run ./owncast to start the service. Visit the admin at /admin to configure your server using the username admin and the default stream key as the password, abc123.</description></item><item><title>Use a container image</title><link>/quickstart/container/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/quickstart/container/</guid><description>Pull the latest version from Dockerhub: docker pull owncast/owncast:latest. Run docker run -v `pwd`/data:/app/data -p 8080:8080 -p 1935:1935 owncast/owncast:latest to start the service. This will bind the data directory so you have access to backups and your database in case you need to move it to another server. Alternatively, you can create a docker-compose.yml file with the following contents:
version: &amp;#34;3&amp;#34; services: owncast: image: owncast/owncast:latest ports: - &amp;#34;8080:8080&amp;#34; - &amp;#34;1935:1935&amp;#34; volumes: - .</description></item><item><title>Configure</title><link>/quickstart/configure/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 20:11:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>/quickstart/configure/</guid><description>While Owncast will work for you out of the box, there are things most people will want to customize after getting it up and running.
Configuration is done through the Owncast administration page located on your server under /admin. The login username is admin and the password is your stream key, the default being abc123.
Some common items many people would want to update after installing Owncast are:
Your site name, logo, description and external links that are displayed on the web site.</description></item><item><title>Start Streaming</title><link>/quickstart/startstreaming/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/quickstart/startstreaming/</guid><description>Any piece of software you&amp;rsquo;re already using for live streaming is likely compatible with Owncast. Visit our broadcasting software page to see some specific pieces of software and how they&amp;rsquo;re configured.
Point your broadcasting software at your new server using rtmp://yourserver/live with your stream key. If your software doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a way to specify a stream key simply use the url rtmp://yourserver/live/streamkey and use your specific stream key instead. Access your server in your web browser by visiting http://yourserver:8080.</description></item><item><title>Next Steps</title><link>/quickstart/nextsteps/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/quickstart/nextsteps/</guid><description>Support HTTPS While not required, most people will want to support SSL on a public Owncast server. If you plan on embedding your Owncast video or chat into another site or are offering your video to the public internet you&amp;rsquo;re likely to need to add a SSL proxy to your setup. Learn more about how to do this.
Run as a system service Most people will want to setup Owncast to automatically start in the background any time their server restarts.</description></item><item><title>Installation</title><link>/quickstart/installation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/quickstart/installation/</guid><description>By using the installer you can get up and running in about a minute. However, if you would prefer to download a release manually, use a one-click install at a supported hosting provider, or use Docker you have those options.
Visit the Quickstart to be walked through the installation options.
Installer Paste the following into your shell and the installer will download the most recent version of Owncast for your platform.</description></item><item><title>Supported one-click installs</title><link>/quickstart/providers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/quickstart/providers/</guid><description>The following service providers offer 1-click-install options for Owncast where you can get up and running without manually installing the software.
Note: The Owncast Project may receive referral credit for deploying Owncast with these options, so it&amp;rsquo;s an easy way to support the project.
Get $100 worth of service for free if you sign up with either of these providers.
Elestio shares portion of it's revenue with Owncast if you choose to deploy on Elestio</description></item><item><title>Owncast Quick Installer</title><link>/quickstart/installer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/quickstart/installer/</guid><description>By using the installer you can get up and running in about a minute. However, if you would prefer to download a release manually, use a one-click install at a supported hosting provider, or other methods visit the Quickstart to find the installation method that best matches your needs.
Installer Paste the following into your shell and the installer will download the most recent version of Owncast for your platform. It will also download a copy of ffmpeg if you don&amp;rsquo;t currently have one installed.</description></item></channel></rss>