<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Owncast Releases on</title><link>/releases/</link><description>Recent content in Owncast Releases on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><atom:link href="/releases/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Owncast v0.0.8</title><link>/releases/owncast-0.0.8/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/releases/owncast-0.0.8/</guid><description>Owncast v0.0.8 features a rewrite of the chat system to improve performance, stability, and user moderation along with changes intended to reduce unauthorized access to chat and its history.
As with all updates it also includes many fixes and improvements to continue improving the self-hosted streaming experience. Please read through the below release notes and let us know what you think about this release. Your feedback drives the roadmap of Owncast, and we want to build the things that are most useful to you.</description></item><item><title>Owncast v0.0.8</title><link>/releases/owncast-0.0.9/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/releases/owncast-0.0.9/</guid><description>Owncast v0.0.9 is a smaller release with a handful of tweaks and fixes. There&amp;rsquo;s not a lot of user-facing changes this time around, but take a look through the below changes and see if there&amp;rsquo;s anything that might impact you.
Upgrade instructions from 0.0.8 Stop the service from running. If you&amp;rsquo;re using a pre-installed image through a hosting provider, or setup Owncast to run under systemd you can probably just simply run systemctl stop owncast.</description></item><item><title>Owncast v0.0.7</title><link>/releases/owncast-0.0.7/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/releases/owncast-0.0.7/</guid><description>This release focuses on a handful of things that should improve the day to day usage of Owncast. The biggest being the ability to use hardware accelerated video codecs and free up your CPU if you&amp;rsquo;re running on dedicated hardware. This is great for people who are hosting from home, even on things like a Raspberry Pi. Other additions people have asked for such as being able to upload your logo directly from the admin, hiding chat, custom CSS, being able to manually select a video stream quality from the player and more are included in this update.</description></item><item><title>Owncast v0.0.6</title><link>/releases/owncast-0.0.6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/releases/owncast-0.0.6/</guid><description>0.0.6 has quite a few changes that impact you, so please take a moment to read about these changes in their entirety.
Upgrade instructions from 0.0.5 Stop the service from running. Download the updated Owncast release for your platform. Move the zip file of 0.0.6 to your previous install location. If you&amp;rsquo;ve customized your web interface in any way you will want to back up the files you&amp;rsquo;ve changed or customized.</description></item><item><title>Owncast v0.0.5</title><link>/releases/owncast-0.0.5/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/releases/owncast-0.0.5/</guid><description>Owncast v0.0.5 focuses primarily on some basic chat moderation, enabling the admin to remove chat messages
Upgrade instructions from 0.0.4 Stop the service from running. Backup your config.yaml and any other files you may have customized and want to save or refer to later. Move the zip file of 0.0.5 to your previous install location. Unzip the file, allowing it to overwrite old files. Restart the service. Changelog Owncast Core:</description></item><item><title>Owncast v0.0.4</title><link>/releases/owncast-0.0.4/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/releases/owncast-0.0.4/</guid><description>v0.0.4 includes several small updates and bug fixes. Also, you can now set a custom RTMP port and use our prepared builds for ARM computers like the Raspberry PI. With our notification feature, your visitors can see that a stream has started and that new chat messages were written while they were in other tabs.
Upgrade instructions from 0.0.3 Stop the service from running. Backup your config.yaml and any other files you may have customized and want to save or refer to later.</description></item><item><title>Owncast v0.0.3</title><link>/releases/owncast-0.0.3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/releases/owncast-0.0.3/</guid><description>v0.0.3 has a new admin dashboard to help get an overview of the configuration and performance of your Owncast server along with handfuls of additional updates.
Owncast Admin v0.0.3 introduces the web admin dashboard that you can use to get an overview of your owncast server.
Visit /admin and login with admin as the username and your stream key as the password.
We will continue to add functionality to this over time, so please let us know how it works for you and if you have any feedback.</description></item><item><title>Owncast v0.0.2</title><link>/releases/owncast-0.0.2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/releases/owncast-0.0.2/</guid><description>v0.0.2 has a bunch of updates, mostly focused on the web frontend.
Major changes Rewrite of the web interface with Preact, removing Vue. [#103] Add support for embedding chat externally. [#96] Add support for embedding the video player externally. [#110] Your username will get highlighted in chat when mentioned. [#100] Emoji picker w/ custom emoji support. [#86] Autocomplete usernames in composing chat messages by hitting tab.</description></item><item><title>Owncast v0.0.1</title><link>/releases/owncast-0.0.1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/releases/owncast-0.0.1/</guid><description>In honor of @mattdsteele and @JCake live streaming their wedding using Owncast tomorrow, here&amp;rsquo;s the first release version.
We&amp;rsquo;ve been testing, doing events and enjoying using Owncast, so I think it&amp;rsquo;s time to have a release version that others can start using as well.
Still lots of exciting updates going on, but here&amp;rsquo;s finally something that you can start using. Feel free to reach out and let us know what you&amp;rsquo;re using Owncast for, or if you have any questions.</description></item></channel></rss>