<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Owncast Releases on</title><link>/releases/</link><description>Recent content in Owncast Releases on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><atom:link href="/releases/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Owncast v0.1.3</title><link>/releases/owncast-0.1.3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/releases/owncast-0.1.3/</guid><description>Changelog [0.1.3] - 2024-04-07 Upgrade instructions from 0.1.2 Stop the service from running. If you&amp;rsquo;re using a pre-installed image through a hosting provider, or setup Owncast to run under systemd you can probably just simply run systemctl stop owncast. Change to the directory where Owncast is installed on your server. If you’ve customized your web interface in any way you will want to back up the files you’ve changed or customized.</description></item><item><title>Owncast v0.1.2</title><link>/releases/owncast-0.1.2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/releases/owncast-0.1.2/</guid><description>Changelog [0.1.2] - 2023-11-18 Upgrade instructions from 0.1.1 Stop the service from running. If you&amp;rsquo;re using a pre-installed image through a hosting provider, or setup Owncast to run under systemd you can probably just simply run systemctl stop owncast. Change to the directory where Owncast is installed on your server. If you’ve customized your web interface in any way you will want to back up the files you’ve changed or customized.</description></item><item><title>Owncast v0.1.1</title><link>/releases/owncast-0.1.1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/releases/owncast-0.1.1/</guid><description>I hope everyone is enjoying all the changes and improvements from the web overhaul that came with v0.1.0. With so many changes we knew there&amp;rsquo;d be a a slew of bug fixes to come along after. And the first round of those are here.
Some changes you might be interested in:
Chat is now re-sizable and there&amp;rsquo;s a convenient way to get the &amp;ldquo;pop-out&amp;rdquo; chat window. Those who use object storage for their steams will now finally see their segments get cleaned up automatically by Owncast without having to configure lifecycle rules with their storage provider.</description></item><item><title>Owncast v0.1.0</title><link>/releases/owncast-0.1.0/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/releases/owncast-0.1.0/</guid><description>Note: Please read these release notes in their entirety. There are many changes and it&amp;rsquo;s important for you to know what has changed and how it will affect you.
Three years of Owncast! The first commit to Owncast was May 23, 2020. It&amp;rsquo;s been a wild ride seeing what everyone has been streaming and all the creative use cases people have come up with. Thank you to everyone who has contributed to the project, and to everyone who has been using it.</description></item><item><title>Owncast v0.0.13</title><link>/releases/owncast-0.0.13/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/releases/owncast-0.0.13/</guid><description>Owncast v0.0.13 is a very small release targeting mostly bug fixes.
Since v0.1.0 is taking longer than hoped, this allows some updates to get out between now and then. But all the work for the new Owncast interface is coming along well and I look forward to getting it finished and putting in everyone&amp;rsquo;s hands.
[0.0.13] - 2022-11-25 Upgrade instructions from 0.0.12 Stop the service from running. If you&amp;rsquo;re using a pre-installed image through a hosting provider, or setup Owncast to run under systemd you can probably just simply run systemctl stop owncast.</description></item><item><title>Owncast v0.0.12</title><link>/releases/owncast-0.0.12/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/releases/owncast-0.0.12/</guid><description>This release has a handful of features, big and small, to improve the overall Owncast experience, primarily around the core streaming and chat functionality.
Chat User Menu This new dropdown menu should help clarify how you change your name, as it was not always clear to all viewers how to do so.
Stream Notifications To assist streamers in automating their live stream announcements, some new ways to notify your viewers and your community have been added.</description></item><item><title>Owncast v0.0.11</title><link>/releases/owncast-0.0.11/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/releases/owncast-0.0.11/</guid><description>Welcome to The Fediverse! With Owncast v0.0.11 your server can optionally become a part of the Fediverse, an interconnected, but completely independent network of servers where people can discover your stream. Some popular Fediverse services are Mastodon and Pleroma but many services that make up the Fediverse can start to receive posts from your Owncast server.
With this ability, it gives you something pretty cool: the ability for people to follow your server and share it with their own followers.</description></item><item><title>Owncast v0.0.10</title><link>/releases/owncast-0.0.10/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/releases/owncast-0.0.10/</guid><description>v0.0.10 is a hot fix to resolve an issue when using external S3 compatible storage in v0.0.9.
There are no other changes and this only impacts those using that feature. See the release notes for v0.0.9 for details around the previous release.
Upgrade instructions from 0.0.9 Stop the service from running. If you&amp;rsquo;re using a pre-installed image through a hosting provider, or setup Owncast to run under systemd you can probably just simply run systemctl stop owncast.</description></item><item><title>Owncast v0.0.9</title><link>/releases/owncast-0.0.9/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/releases/owncast-0.0.9/</guid><description>Owncast v0.0.9 is a smaller release with a handful of tweaks and fixes. There&amp;rsquo;s not a lot of user-facing changes this time around, but take a look through the below changes and see if there&amp;rsquo;s anything that might impact you.
One thing that might make your life more convenient going forward is instead of putting in the full video URL /hls/stream.m3u8 when viewing an Owncast stream in an external video player (MPV, Quicktime, VLC) you can just put your root URL to your Owncast server.</description></item><item><title>Owncast v0.0.8</title><link>/releases/owncast-0.0.8/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/releases/owncast-0.0.8/</guid><description>Owncast v0.0.8 features a rewrite of the chat system to improve performance, stability, and user moderation along with changes intended to reduce unauthorized access to chat and its history.
As with all updates it also includes many fixes and improvements to continue improving the self-hosted streaming experience. Please read through the below release notes and let us know what you think about this release. Your feedback drives the roadmap of Owncast, and we want to build the things that are most useful to you.</description></item></channel></rss>