<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Troubleshoot Common Problems on</title><link>/troubleshoot/</link><description>Recent content in Troubleshoot Common Problems on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><atom:link href="/troubleshoot/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>/troubleshoot/shared/add-lower-quality-outputs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/troubleshoot/shared/add-lower-quality-outputs/</guid><description>Adding additional, lower, qualities within your Owncast video configuration will give these people smaller video to download, therefore downloading faster and resulting in less buffering. Lower bitrate, framerate and resolution are available combinations of settings you can utilize to offer low quality options for your viewers.
Drawback: Adding additional qualities will result in using more hardware resources on your server, so keep an eye on your CPU usage as you make these changes.</description></item><item><title/><link>/troubleshoot/shared/broadcasting-disconnected/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/troubleshoot/shared/broadcasting-disconnected/</guid><description>Make sure you have a supported version of ffmpeg on your Owncast server. Download ffmpeg 4.1.5 or above. Look at your owncast logs in the console or your admin. There may be specific error messages to tell you what you can do next. Take a look at transcoder.log for detailed logging that you can provide when asking for help if you don&amp;rsquo;t see anything in the Owncast logs. Make sure your copy of ffmpeg was not installed via Snap packages, as the sandboxing of Snap distributed software isn&amp;rsquo;t compatible in this case.</description></item><item><title/><link>/troubleshoot/shared/broadcasting-software/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/troubleshoot/shared/broadcasting-software/</guid><description>Make sure your broadcasting computer is broadcasting live video reliably. If your own computer or network connection is having a hard time getting video to the internet then viewers will be stuck in a buffering state. Reduce the bitrate, resolution and/or framerate in your broadcasting software on broadcasting device if needed.
Take note of any dropped frames and investigate what’s causing those drops. Is it your local CPU or GPU? Is it your local network?</description></item><item><title/><link>/troubleshoot/shared/chat-disabled/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/troubleshoot/shared/chat-disabled/</guid><description>The chat is only enabled when a stream is active. This is to stop drive-by spammy chat messages by people when no stream is taking place.
If you&amp;rsquo;re using a proxy in front of your Owncast instance make sure it is configured properly to support websockets. By default some do not pass along the websocket properly. Read your proxy documentation to make sure websocket support is configured properly to support Owncast chat.</description></item><item><title/><link>/troubleshoot/shared/cpu-usage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/troubleshoot/shared/cpu-usage/</guid><description>If your hardware is being maxed out then your video may not be processed and delivered fast enough to keep up with the real-time requirements of live video.
Each stream output quality adds significant CPU usage and slows down the overall generation of video segments. It&amp;rsquo;s generally advised to start with one output, and then add additional, one at a time, to see how it impacts your CPU usage.
If your CPU is being over-utilized, here are some steps you can try taking to resolve this.</description></item><item><title/><link>/troubleshoot/shared/hardware-usage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/troubleshoot/shared/hardware-usage/</guid><description>Visit the hardware usage page in the admin to see how your server&amp;rsquo;s resources are performing.
If your CPU is maxed out on your Owncast server viewers will see buffering, as the server can no longer keep up. If this is what you&amp;rsquo;re experiencing the first step is to resolve excessive hardware utilization.</description></item><item><title/><link>/troubleshoot/shared/hls-analyzer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/troubleshoot/shared/hls-analyzer/</guid><description>Visit HLS Analyzer to assist in troubleshooting. Put in your stream URL when asked, it is &amp;lt;yourserver&amp;gt;/hls/stream.m3u8. Hit Analyze .m3u8.
Take note of the following values:
Segment Download (sec): The amount of time it took (in seconds) to download one segment of video. If it takes longer to download one segment of video than each segment lasts you will get buffering.
Player Buffer (sec): The amount of playable video (in seconds) available.</description></item><item><title/><link>/troubleshoot/shared/low-quality-video/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/troubleshoot/shared/low-quality-video/</guid><description>Your stream, at the very least, is only as good as what you&amp;rsquo;re sending to Owncast. So make sure you&amp;rsquo;re sending from your broadcasting software at a quality that you&amp;rsquo;re happy with. Read through our Broadcasting Software Suggestions where some specifics are listed for your software.
You may also want to increase the amount of CPU being used to process the video on your Owncast server. As you go lower you will visibly see the quality degrade.</description></item><item><title/><link>/troubleshoot/shared/match-highest-output-quality/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/troubleshoot/shared/match-highest-output-quality/</guid><description>One easy optimization for CPU usage is to make sure your inbound video matches your highest output quality.
The highest bitrate, resolution and framerate quality you have configured in Owncast to offer your viewers should match what you&amp;rsquo;re sending Owncast in your broadcasting software to reduce the amount of extra CPU work it needs to do. Start with your highest quality matching your broadcasting software and then go from there. Lower qualities, of course, should be offered for people with slower network connections or are geographically distant.</description></item><item><title/><link>/troubleshoot/shared/misc-video-issues/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/troubleshoot/shared/misc-video-issues/</guid><description>Make sure you have video passthrough disabled. I know you want to keep it on, but if you&amp;rsquo;re having issues TURN IT OFF. If that doesn&amp;rsquo;t fix it, then you can turn it back on later when you figure out the problem. Look at your Owncast logs as well as transcoder.log to see if there are any errors that might be helpful. To troubleshoot try a different source and/or a different player so when you ask for help you can know that it works for X but doesn&amp;rsquo;t work for Y.</description></item></channel></rss>