<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Documentation on</title><link>/docs/</link><description>Recent content in Documentation on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><atom:link href="/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Configuration</title><link>/docs/configuration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/configuration/</guid><description>Configuration is done through the Owncast administration page located on your server under /admin. The login username is admin and the password is your stream key, the default being abc123.
Some common items many people would want to update after installing Owncast are:
Your site name, logo, description and external links that are displayed on the web site. The stream key to gain access to broadcasting to your stream and your admin.</description></item><item><title>Chat authentication</title><link>/docs/chat-authentication/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/chat-authentication/</guid><description>There is no requirement to authenticate when using Owncast chat. However, some prefer to authenticate themselves to verify their identity to others, and to continue using the same chat identity across multiple devices and browsers. This is especially helpful for those with moderator privileges.
You can access the authentication options via the chat dropdown menu in the upper right of the page.
IndieAuth IndieAuth is an open standard decentralized authentication protocol that enables services to verify the identity of a user represented by a URL.</description></item><item><title>Embedding into your site</title><link>/docs/embed/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/embed/</guid><description>💡 Embedding Owncast into an existing page which is using HTTPS will require your Owncast server to also be secured with SSL/TLS. Embedding video Owncast supports embedding your video stream directly into any other web site or source without having to setup a player.
The video-only URL to your stream content lives at: http://your.host/embed/video.
Here&amp;rsquo;s some example HTML you can use.
&amp;lt;iframe src=&amp;#34;https://your.host/embed/video&amp;#34; title=&amp;#34;Owncast&amp;#34; height=&amp;#34;350px&amp;#34; width=&amp;#34;550px&amp;#34; referrerpolicy=&amp;#34;origin&amp;#34; scrolling=&amp;#34;no&amp;#34; allowfullscreen&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/iframe&amp;gt; Embedding video was first supported in Owncast 0.</description></item><item><title>Live stream notifications</title><link>/docs/notifications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/notifications/</guid><description>Some streams benefit from announcing to their audience when they go live.
This is not an endorsement of any particular service, but it may help some streamers integrate into their existing communities.
If you&amp;rsquo;d like to expand on this and send automated notifications to other destinations, create a custom webhook.
External notification was first supported in Owncast 0.0.12. Browser notifications Using browser push notifications your viewers can choose to be notified each time you go live.</description></item><item><title>Run as a system service</title><link>/docs/systemservice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/systemservice/</guid><description>You can optionally setup Owncast to run under systemd so it&amp;rsquo;s a managed service on your machine that automatically starts when your machine does.
While we can&amp;rsquo;t explicitly support every possible machine&amp;rsquo;s configuration you might be able to find some user-supplied examples in our contrib directory that might point you in the correct direction.
These files are not part of the Owncast project and are not supported by us, but there is ample documentation about how to configure systemd online if you&amp;rsquo;re unable to find examples that work for you.</description></item><item><title>Social features</title><link>/docs/social/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/social/</guid><description>Owncast allows people to follow, engage with your server, and share your stream with others on what is known as the Fediverse, a decentralized network of services.
Social functionality was first supported in Owncast 0.0.11. What it supports People can follow your server. Your followers show up in the &amp;ldquo;Followers&amp;rdquo; tab on your stream&amp;rsquo;s page. You can send out posts to your followers via the admin. Your followers will automatically get notified when you go live.</description></item><item><title>Stream performance</title><link>/docs/metrics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/metrics/</guid><description>Overall stream health There&amp;rsquo;s no point streaming if nobody is able to watch it. Using the &amp;ldquo;Stream Health&amp;rdquo; screen in the admin you can get an overview of some important metrics that may give you an idea if what you&amp;rsquo;re offering your viewers is leading to a good experience.
Seeing errors, low network speeds, and excessive download times for your content may mean you need to add additional video qualities to improve the playback performance for lower bandwidth viewers, mobile networks, or other factors.</description></item><item><title>Chat moderation</title><link>/docs/moderation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/moderation/</guid><description>Using either the Owncast admin, or inline moderation controls within your chat, you can remove individual messages or entire users.
Chat Moderators Moderators have no access to the admin, and exist to help you keep your chat in order.
In your admin Visit Chat &amp;amp; Users &amp;gt; Users to find the user you want to grant Moderator privileges. Bring up their details and you can add them as a moderator.</description></item><item><title>Troubleshooting</title><link>/docs/troubleshooting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/troubleshooting/</guid><description>CPU and RAM usage alerts If your hardware is being maxed out then your video may not be processed and delivered fast enough to keep up with the real-time requirements of live video.
Here are some steps you can try taking to resolve this.
You may have too many video outputs defined in your settings. Try limiting yourself to a single output, and go from there. Change your settings to use less cpu.</description></item><item><title>Web Site + Chat</title><link>/docs/website/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/website/</guid><description>Overview Owncast includes a web interface for your video with built-in chat that is available once you start the server. It shows online/offline states, viewer counts, stream duration, your instance&amp;rsquo;s description, images, links and more. You can just start using it without making any changes, but you&amp;rsquo;ll likely want to update the content displayed on your page by visiting your server admin page.
Additionally, the web interface was specifically built to be editable by anybody comfortable tweaking a web page.</description></item></channel></rss>