<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Documentation on</title><link>/docs/</link><description>Recent content in Documentation on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><atom:link href="/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Configuration</title><link>/docs/configuration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/configuration/</guid><description>Configuration is done through the Owncast administration page located on your server under /admin. The login username is admin and the password is your stream key, the default being abc123.
It&amp;rsquo;s highly encouraged to change both your stream key and your admin passwords immediately after installation by visiting /admin/config/server/
Some common items many people would want to update after installing Owncast are:
Your site name, logo, description and external links that are displayed on the web site.</description></item><item><title>Chat authentication</title><link>/docs/chat/chat-authentication/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/chat/chat-authentication/</guid><description>There is no requirement to authenticate when using Owncast chat. However, some prefer to authenticate themselves to verify their identity to others, and to continue using the same chat identity across multiple devices and browsers. This is especially helpful for those with moderator privileges.
You can access the authentication options via the chat dropdown menu in the upper right of the page.
IndieAuth IndieAuth is an open standard decentralized authentication protocol that enables services to verify the identity of a user represented by a URL.</description></item><item><title>Content Delivery Networks (CDNs)</title><link>/docs/cdns/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/cdns/</guid><description>What is a CDN? A CDN, or Content Delivery Network, is a service used to geographically distribute your content to end users. It helps to improve performance by reducing the time it takes to load content.
Cdn support was first supported in Owncast 0.1.0. 💡 While the actual configuration of a CDN is not overly complex, it should be seen as a slightly advanced topic as you'll be making DNS changes and managing a CDN configuration with a provider.</description></item><item><title>Embedding into your site</title><link>/docs/embed/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/embed/</guid><description>💡 Embedding Owncast into an existing page which is using HTTPS will require your Owncast server to also be secured with SSL/TLS. Embedding video Owncast supports embedding your video stream directly into any other web site or source without having to setup a player.
The video-only URL to your stream content lives at: http://your.host/embed/video.
Here&amp;rsquo;s some example HTML you can use.
&amp;lt;iframe src=&amp;#34;https://your.host/embed/video&amp;#34; title=&amp;#34;Owncast&amp;#34; height=&amp;#34;350px&amp;#34; width=&amp;#34;550px&amp;#34; referrerpolicy=&amp;#34;origin&amp;#34; allowfullscreen&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/iframe&amp;gt; Embedding video was first supported in Owncast 0.</description></item><item><title>Host public assets</title><link>/docs/custom-assets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/custom-assets/</guid><description>By creating a data/public directory and putting your own files there you can serve any assets that you wish to make publicly available for any reason.
Custom public assets was first supported in Owncast 0.1.0. Some exmples of reasons you might want to take advantage of this:
Making a CSS font available so you can reference it in your custom CSS. You have images you wish to use in your page content.</description></item><item><title>Live stream notifications</title><link>/docs/notifications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/notifications/</guid><description>Some streams benefit from announcing to their audience when they go live.
This is not an endorsement of any particular service, but it may help some streamers integrate into their existing communities.
If you&amp;rsquo;d like to expand on this and send automated notifications to other destinations, create a custom webhook.
External notification was first supported in Owncast 0.0.12. Browser notifications Using browser push notifications your viewers can choose to be notified each time you go live.</description></item><item><title>Resources and requirements</title><link>/docs/resources-requirements/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/resources-requirements/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s impossible to give a single answer about what the requirements are for you to run Owncast, or what it will cost. It&amp;rsquo;s your server, and it&amp;rsquo;s completely up to you how you choose to configure it, and in what environments you choose to run it. Every environment has different performance, prices and features.
Base knowledge It&amp;rsquo;s very helpful for you to understand the basics included in video streaming.
CPU: Used to transcode the video to multiple qualities so viewers can watch it on different speed networks.</description></item><item><title>Run as a system service</title><link>/docs/systemservice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/systemservice/</guid><description>You can optionally setup Owncast to run under systemd so it&amp;rsquo;s a managed service on your machine that automatically starts when your machine does.
While we can&amp;rsquo;t explicitly support every possible machine&amp;rsquo;s configuration you might be able to find some user-supplied examples in our contrib directory that might point you in the correct direction.
These files are not part of the Owncast project and are not supported by us, but there is ample documentation about how to configure systemd online if you&amp;rsquo;re unable to find examples that work for you.</description></item><item><title>Social features</title><link>/docs/social/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/social/</guid><description>Owncast allows people to follow, engage with your server, and share your stream with others on what is known as the Fediverse, a decentralized network of services.
Social functionality was first supported in Owncast 0.0.11. What it supports People can follow your server. Your followers show up in the &amp;ldquo;Followers&amp;rdquo; tab on your stream&amp;rsquo;s page. You can send out posts to your followers via the admin. Your followers will automatically get notified when you go live.</description></item><item><title>Stream Keys</title><link>/docs/stream-keys/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/stream-keys/</guid><description>Beginning with Owncast v0.1.0 the admin password and stream keys are managed independently, allowing you to add as many stream keys as you&amp;rsquo;d like.
Multiple stream keys was first supported in Owncast 0.1.0. While most people won&amp;rsquo;t require having multiple stream keys, there are some specific scenarios where having this ability may be helpful.
In the admin server setup page you can add and remove these keys.</description></item></channel></rss>